A Guide to the Additional Papers of Louis I. Jaffé, ca. 1907-1993
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Louis I. Jaffé ca. 1907-1993
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
9924-o
This addition to the Louis I. Jaffé Papers, consists of ca. 900 items (5 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear shelf feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the University of Virginia Library on February 3, 2001 by Louis I. Jaffé, Jr.
Scope and Content
This addition to the Louis I. Jaffé Papers, ca. 1907 - 1993, consists of ca. 900 items (5 Hollinger boxes, ca. 2 linear shelf feet) including correspondence, articles, newspapers clippings and other printed materials, and photographs. Little of the material was collected by Jaffé in his capacity as editor of the Virginia Pilot. Rather, it relates to his personal life or earlier employment or was collected by his wife after his death.
Items collected by Alice Jaffé after her husband's death include tributes to Jaffe- and writings and correspondence about him. Other materials relate to Jaffé's early life as a student at Trinity College, a soldier in World War I, a member of the Red Cross Commission to the Balkan States, and a fledgling newspaperman in Durham, North Carolina and Richmond Virginia. The collection also includes many of his personal items: correspondence with his family and friends, diaries, date books, and medical, legal, and financial documents. The collection also contains Alice Jaffé's correspondence with Lélège Potin, her "French war orphan," as well as two photograph albums of the Potin family.
Arrangement
The order imposed by Mrs. Jaffé has been maintained.
Contents List
- Series I: Topical Files
  - American Red Cross 1919, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Diplomas and Certificates belonging to Louis Jaffe? and Alice Cohn Rice (oversize) 1907-1930 (Box 1)
  - "Duke University's Bid for Greatness" by Louis Jaffe? n.d. (Box 1)
  - Europe - Items related to Jaffé's travel in Europe during and after World War I 1917 - 1919, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Europe - Items related to Jaffé's travel in Europe in 1937 1937, n.d. (Box 1)
  - "A Glimpse of Parnassus: The Travels of Louis I. Jaffé" by Alonzo Thomas Dill n.d. (Box 1)
  - "A Glimpse of Parnassus: The Travels of Louis I. Jaffé" by Alonzo Thomas Dill, research notes for n.d. (Box 1)
  - Jaffé, Christopher - Louis Jaffé's son from first marriage 1922 - 1940, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Louis Jaffé - biographical sketch; birthday tributes n.d. (Box 1)
  - Louis Jaffé - Financial 1907 - 1949 (Box 1)
  - Louis Jaffé - Marriages and divorce 1920 - 1942 (Box 1)
  - Louis Jaffé - Medical 1936 - 1947 (Box 1)
  - Journal kept by Louis Jaffé during World War I 1917 - 1918 (Box 1)
  - Memberships, addresses, business cards, notes 1915 - 1950 (Box 1)
  - Memorial Necrology (oversize) 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Military papers - World War I 1917 - 1919, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Military papers - World War I - U.S. Army Transport Service Passenger List (oversize) n.d. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous 1949, n.d. (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (oversize) 1972, n.d. (Box 1)
  - News clippings - Jaffé family 1913 -1993, n.d. (Box 2)
  - News clippings - about Jaffé saved by Alice Jaffé 1926 - 1948, n.d. (Box 2)
  - News clippings by Jaffé 1908 - 1950 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - marked "personal" by Alice Jaffé 1919 - 1949 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - re: Jaffé 1911 - 1988, n.d. (Box 2)
  - News clippings - re: Jaffé family members 1936 - 1978, n.d. (Box 2)
  - News clippings - re: Jaffé - obituaries 1950 (Box 2)
  - News clippings - re: World War I, collected by Jaffé 1918 (Box 2)
  - Norfolk, Virginia 1938 - 1984, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs - Louis Jaffé and Jaffé family 1918 - 1972, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs - World War I 1919, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Photographs - Second Battery, Training Camp, Fort Myer (oversize) 1917 Aug 30 (Box 2)
  - "The Political Problem of the Solid South" by Henry W. Anderson n.d. (Box 2)
  - Pulitzer Prize for Journalism 1929-80 (Box 2)
  - Trinity College/Duke University 1911 - 1948, n.d. (Box 2)
- Series II: Correspondence and Abstracts of Correspondence
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé 1950 - 1988, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé and Alderman Library 1973 - 1986 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé and Lenoir Chambers 1957 - 1969 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé and Alonzo Thomas Dill 1975 - 1990, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé and descendents of Louis I. Jaffé 1974 - 1989 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Alice Jaffé and Potin family 1918 - 1990, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis and Alice Jaffé and the Newberry Library re: papers of Sherwood Anderson 1943 - 1973 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé 1907 - 1950, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé and Christopher Jaffé (son) 1937 - 1939 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé and his parents 1920 - 1942, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé and Hyman (brother) and Hattie (sister-in-law) Jaffé 1917 - 1937, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé and Margaret Davis Jaffé (first wife) 1920 - 1943, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé with the Richmond Times Dispatch 1911 - 1914 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé with the Virginia Pilot 1919, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Louis I. Jaffé and Thomas Wheelwright 1931 - 1935 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Re: divorce of Louis I. Jaffé and Margaret Davis 1929 - 1940 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Re: Louis Jaffé 1914 - 1990, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Correspondence - Re: Norfolk Joint Commission for Negro Welfare Center 1944 - 1947, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the correspondence of Louis Jaffé, A-E n.d (Box 4)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the correspondence of Louis Jaffé, E-N n.d. (Box 4)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the correspondence of Louis Jaffé, N-Z n.d. (Box 4)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the papers of Louis Jaffé, subsidiary file I n.d. (Box 4)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the papers of Louis Jaffé, subsidiary file II n.d. (Box 4)
  - Abstracts by Alice Jaffé on the papers of Louis Jaffé, collection 9924-o n.d. (Box 4)
  - notebook c. 1923 (Box 4)
  - Articles and speeches by Louis I. Jaffé, editor, Virginian-Pilot, 1919-1950 1986 (Box 4)
  - Photographs of the Potin family (2 albums) 1918 - 1963 (Box 4)
  - Datebooks (12) 1937, 1940 - 1950 (Box 5)
  - Notebook c. 1917 (Box 5)
  - Address book c. 1918 (Box 5)